Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Anthony Rau papers, 1946-1986 and undated RL.11460
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Anthony Rau papers
1946-1986 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11460
8.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The JWT London office first opened in 1899. Anthony Rau was an executive with the London office whose career spanned the 1960s-1980s. Collection includes correspondence, research and status reports, brochures and other printed materials, and other materials that document Rau's work at JWT London in new business acquisition and JWT's charitable efforts. Companies represented include British Petroleum (BP), British Rail, Charities Aid Foundation, Singer, RCA, Tesco and United Biscuits. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: General Files; New Business Account Files.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Anthony Rau papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. New Business records; J. Walter Thompson Company. Account Files; J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office records; J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office advertisements.
Collection Overview
Includes correspondence, research and status reports, brochures and other printed materials, and other materials that document Rau's work at JWT London in new business acquisition and JWT's charitable efforts. Companies represented include British Petroleum (BP), British Rail, Charities Aid Foundation, Singer, RCA, Tesco and United Biscuits. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The JWT London office first opened in 1899. Anthony Rau was an executive with the London office whose career spanned the 1960s-1980s.
Advertising; Advertising -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising executives; Marketing research; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Singer Sewing Machine Company; Radio Corporation of America
- General Files, 1962-1986 and undated; 1
  - 100 Facts about JWT (Peter Nevile), 1965 (Box 1)
  - Charity work--CAM (Communication Advertising and Marketing Education Foundation), 1982 (Box 1)
  - Charity work--Charity tie-ins, 1979-1983; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Charity work--History of Advertising Trust, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Charity work--JWT charitable donations, 1966-1969; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Charity work--JWT charitable donations, 1969; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Charity work--JWT charities, 1980-1982; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Charity work--JWT Charity Committee, 1973-1975; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Charity work--JWT Charity Committee, 1970-1979 (Box 3)
  - Charity work--JWT/Charities Aid Foundation, 1970-1980; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Group new business, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Hill & Knowlton, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - J. Walter Thompson philosophy, undated (Box 3)
  - Jeremy Bullmore Admap article, 1984 (Box 3)
  - JWT: A Compendium of Facts, undated (Box 3)
  - JWT credentials booklet, 1966 (Box 3)
  - JWt London advertisement: Have You Got What It Takes to Be a Top Heavyweight, undated (Box 3)
  - JWT London company charts, 1984 (Box 3)
  - JWT London credentials, 1962-1965 (Box 3)
  - JWT Service and Organisation, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Landsdowne Marketing--Business and Communication Plan; New Business Objectives, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Landsdowne Marketing--Overview, 1979 (Box 4)
  - MARC (Management and Applied Research Consultants), 1984 (Box 4)
  - Memos, 1972-1984 (Box 4)
  - New Business Committee meeting minutes, 1966-1983; 7 folders (Box 4)
  - New Business Committee meeting minutes, 1984-1986; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - New Business Group meeting minutes, 1980 (Box 5)
  - New business notes for Board meetings, 1971-1978 (Box 5)
  - New business presentation charts, 1966 (Box 5)
  - New Business Seminar (training), 1966; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Reports--Annual Marketing Reports, 1968-1970 (Box 5)
  - Reports--European new business, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - Reports--Guide to Television, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Reports--JWT Market Report: Reinforcing the Sales Force, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Reports--Miscellaneous new business reports, 1962-1966 (Box 6)
  - Reports--Monthly New Business Report, 1966-1973; 8 folders (Box 6)
  - Reports--Monthly New Business Report, 1974-1980; 7 folders (Box 7)
  - Reports--Monthly New Business Report, 1981-1983; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Reports--Monthly New Business Report--Memos, 1962-1968 (Box 8)
  - Reports--Proposals for a Major Italian Wine Promotion in the United Kingdom, 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - Reports--Recent Developments at J. Walter Thompson Company Ltd., 1966 (Box 8)
  - Reports--Some Details About J. Walter Thompson Company Ltd., 1967 (Box 8)
  - Reports--Summary of New Business Contacts, 1963-1965 (Box 8)
  - Reports--Testing to Destruction (Alan Hedges), 1974 (Box 8)
  - Reports--Weekly Information Service, 1983-1986 (Box 8)
- New Business Account Files, 1946-1985 and undated; 2
  - Contacts, 1946-1985 and undated; 1
    - Bache, 1973 (Box 9)
    - Bacofoil, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Balcan Engineering, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Batchelor's Foods, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Battersea Trading, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Baxter's, 1973-1984 (Box 9)
    - Bayer, 1974 (Box 9)
    - Beecham, 1973-1982 (Box 9)
    - Beef Information Council, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Beefeater Gin, 1968-1980 (Box 9)
    - Bees Limited, 1973-1976 (Box 9)
    - Belfast Trust, 1974 (Box 9)
    - Benelux Musical Instruments, 1974 (Box 9)
    - Bent Cross Shopping Centre, 1973-1978 (Box 9)
    - Bentley Organ, 1974 (Box 9)
    - Berger, 1973-1980 (Box 9)
    - Berlei, 1975-1979 (Box 9)
    - Bicycles, 1976-1980 (Box 9)
    - Blackpool Illuminations, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Blue Circle Group, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Bob Martin Export Company, 1980-1983 (Box 18)
    - Book Promotion, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Booker Belmont Foods, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Bovis Homes, 1972-1974 (Box 9)
    - Bowater Scott, 1972-1982 (Box 9)
    - Braun, 1973-1978 (Box 9)
    - Brentford Nylons, 1976 (Box 9)
    - British Aircraft, 1973 (Box 9)
    - British Airports Authority, 1974-1978 (Box 9)
    - British Airways, 1972-1982 (Box 9)
    - British American Tobacco, 1972 (Box 9)
    - British Electrical and Allied Manufacturers Association; British Electrical Development Association, 1961-1965 (Box 9)
    - British Electronics Industry; British Farm Produce Council; British Home Stores; British Nylon Spinners, 1960-1985 (Box 10)
    - British Lion Films, 1973-1976 (Box 10)
    - British Mail Order Corporation, 1972 (Box 10)
    - British Overseas Air Corporation (BOAC), 1973 (Box 10)
    - British Petroleum, 1960-1985; 4 folders (Box 10)
    - British Plastics, 1973 (Box 10)
    - British Poultry Association, 1973-1981 (Box 10)
    - British Rail, 1975-1983 (Box 10)
    - British Rail Shipping Services, 1966-1982 (Box 10)
    - British Rail Shipping Services, 1966-1982 (Box 11)
    - British Railways, 1960-1962 (Box 11)
    - British Railways--Ireland, 1966-1967 (Box 11)
    - British Red Cross, 1976 (Box 11)
    - British Seagull, 1977 (Box 11)
    - British Steel, 1974-1978 (Box 11)
    - British Transport Commission, 1955-1962 (Box 11)
    - British Veterinary Association, 1977 (Box 11)
    - Brooke Bond, 1955-1978 (Box 11)
    - Buckell & Ballard, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Building Material Producers, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Buitoni Foods, 1967 (Box 11)
    - BUPA, 1974-1984 (Box 11)
    - Burmah Castrol, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Burton's, 1962-1972 (Box 11)
    - Butlins, 1949-1984 (Box 11)
    - Butter Information Council, 1973-1979 (Box 11)
    - Canada Office of Tourism, undated (Box 11)
    - Charles Barker, 1974 (Box 11)
    - European Button Industries, 1973 (Box 11)
    - G.B. Britton, 1962-1968 (Box 12)
    - H.P. Bulmers, 1967-1969 (Box 12)
    - Henry Boot, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
    - Hoechst, 1971-1972 (Box 18)
    - International Spike, 1978 (Box 18)
    - J--Miscellaneous, 1973-1985 (Box 18)
    - J&B Whisky, 1977-1978 (Box 18)
    - Jacobs Coffee, 1976-1983 (Box 18)
    - Jaguar, 1980 (Box 18)
    - James Buchanan (Black & White Whisky), 1976-1977 (Box 12)
    - James Robertson and Sons Preserve Manufacturers, 1975 (Box 18)
    - Jamieson Mackay & Partners, 1977 (Box 18)
    - Jantzen, 1975 (Box 18)
    - Japan Airlines, 1982 (Box 18)
    - Jeans--Levi Strauss, 1973-1982; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Jeans--Lois, Mint, 1975-1976 (Box 18)
    - Jeyes Group, 1975 (Box 18)
    - Johnson (H&R)/Crystal Ceramic Tiles, 1980 (Box 18)
    - Johnson (S.C.) Wax, 1973-1985; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Johnson & Johnson, 1983 (Box 18)
    - Johnson Matthey, 1974 (Box 18)
    - Jovan, 1975-1979 (Box 18)
    - Jubilee Sailing Trust, 1981 (Box 18)
    - K--Miscellaneous, 1974-1978 (Box 18)
    - K Shoes, 1974-1982 (Box 18)
    - Kawasaki, 1976-1979 (Box 18)
    - KCA Minerals, 1983 (Box 18)
    - Kellogg, 1973-1979 (Box 18)
    - Kentucky Fried Chicken, 1974-1982 (Box 18)
    - King Edward VII Hospital, 1978 (Box 18)
    - Kintracers Limited, 1978 (Box 18)
    - Kitty Litter, 1983-1985 (Box 18)
    - Knight Frank & Rutley, 1975 (Box 18)
    - Knirps Umbrellas, 1981 (Box 18)
    - Knorr (Italian, Spanish, Dutch), 1974-1977 (Box 19)
    - Kodak/Kalle Infotec, 1971-1985 (Box 19)
    - Kores Nordic, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Kraft, 1972-1980 (Box 19)
    - Krug, 1974-1977 (Box 19)
    - L--Miscellaneous, 1973-1985 (Box 19)
    - Ladbrokes Co. Limited, 1973-1974 (Box 19)
    - Laindon Holdings, 1974-1975 (Box 19)
    - Lanier Business Products, 1976 (Box 19)
    - Laserium, 1977 (Box 19)
    - Law Society, 1976-1983 (Box 19)
    - Lawsons of Dyce, 1974-1976 (Box 19)
    - Leeds Permanent Building Society, 1976-1977 (Box 19)
    - Legal & General Group plc, 1974-1984 (Box 19)
    - Lego, 1973 (Box 19)
    - Levers New Zealand, 1976-1978 (Box 19)
    - Lion International/Ransom (film), 1973-1974 (Box 19)
    - Loctite, 1977-1982 (Box 19)
    - London Clearing Bankers, 1976 (Box 19)
    - London Transport, 1976 (Box 19)
    - Lotus Development Corporation, 1984 (Box 19)
    - Lucas, 1977-1979 (Box 19)
    - Lufthansa, 1984-1985 (Box 19)
    - Lufthansa, 1980-1984 (Box 12)
    - Lustraphone, 1973 (Box 19)
    - Lux, 1974 (Box 19)
    - Lyons Maid, 1976-1977 (Box 19)
    - M--Miscellaneous, 1973-1985 (Box 19)
    - Makro International, 1974-1978 (Box 19)
    - Manchester Tobacco, 1983 (Box 19)
    - Manpower Services Commission, 1985 (Box 19)
    - Marfleet Refining, 1983 (Box 19)
    - Mark Allan Travel, 1979-1980 (Box 19)
    - Mark Eden (bust developer), 1973 (Box 19)
    - Marks and Spencer, 1974-1982 (Box 20)
    - Mars/Uncle Ben's (Belgium), 1977 (Box 20)
    - Marsh & McLennan, 1973-1982 (Box 20)
    - Martini & Rossi, 1975-1983 (Box 20)
    - Maruman Sports, 1978 (Box 20)
    - MAS (Malaysian Airlines System), 1975-1979 (Box 20)
    - Mass Marketing (Mass Consultants), 1975-1977 (Box 20)
    - Mattel UK, 1985 (Box 20)
    - Max Factor, 1980 (Box 20)
    - Mayborn, 1984 (Box 20)
    - McDonald's, 1974-1978 (Box 20)
    - Measurement Aids Ltd., 1971-1974 (Box 20)
    - Meat & Livestock Commission, 1974-1984 (Box 20)
    - Meat Marketing Board, 1962-1963 (Box 20)
    - Medical Research Council, 1979 (Box 20)
    - Mellon Bank, 1981 (Box 20)
    - Metaxa, 1980-1984 (Box 20)
    - Michelin, 1976-1979 (Box 20)
    - Midas Muffler, 1978-1984 (Box 20)
    - Midland Bank, 1975 (Box 20)
    - Milk Marketing Board, 1973-1984 (Box 20)
    - Millioniser 2000 (music synthesizer), 1983 (Box 20)
    - Milton Bradley, 1977-1984 (Box 20)
    - Milton Keynes, 1980-1983 (Box 20)
    - Minnesota Mining & Manufacturing (3M), 1978 (Box 20)
    - Mint market (Tic Tac, Dynamint), 1975-1976 (Box 20)
    - Mitsubishi, 1974-1975 (Box 20)
    - Mitsui Petrochemical Industries, 1979-1980 (Box 20)
    - Monaco Real Estate, 1975 (Box 20)
    - Monsanto, 1973-1978 (Box 20)
    - Morocco, 1983 (Box 20)
    - Mullard, 1975 (Box 20)
    - Mysore Sales (India), 1974 (Box 20)
    - N-Miscellaneous, 1973-1983 (Box 20)
    - National Airlines, 1978-1979 (Box 20)
    - National Bus/National Travel, 1972-1981 (Box 20)
    - National Computing Centre, 1978-1979 (Box 20)
    - National Dairy Council, 1974 (Box 20)
    - National Farmers Union, 1974-1984 (Box 21)
    - National Panasonic, 1976 (Box 21)
    - Nationalised Industries Chairmen's Group, 1976 (Box 21)
    - Nationwide Building Society, 1974-1976 (Box 21)
    - NatWest (National Westminster Bank), 1973-1985 (Box 21)
    - Neckermann Travel/Touristic Union International (Germany), 1977-1978; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Nestle, 1974-1985 (Box 21)
    - New Perspectives Publishing, 1974 (Box 21)
    - New Zealand (Meat, Lamb, Dairy, Apple & Pear marketing associations), 1972-1985 (Box 21)
    - Nigeria (A. Shobanjo, Insight Communications), 1982 (Box 21)
    - Nigerian Airways, 1975 (Box 21)
    - Nikon, 1981 (Box 21)
    - Norman Frizzell Motor and General, 1976-1977 (Box 21)
    - North Thames Gas Board, 1974 (Box 21)
    - North-Western Gas, 1981 (Box 21)
    - Northern Telecom, 1976 (Box 21)
    - Norwegian Aluminium (A/S Nordisk Aluminiumindustri, 1975 (Box 21)
    - Norwich Union Insurance, 1977-1981 (Box 21)
    - Radio Corporation of America (RCA), 1960-1974; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Radio Rentals, 1952-1967 (Box 12)
    - Rael Brook, 1958-1963 (Box 12)
    - Raleigh Industries, 1965-1975 (Box 12)
    - Rank Hovis McDougall, 1971-1973 (Box 12)
    - Rank Organisation, 1961-1968 (Box 12)
    - Safeway, 1961-1974 (Box 13)
    - Sainsbury, 1976-1977 (Box 13)
    - Scottish Gas, 1963 (Box 13)
    - Seven Up, 1952-1962 (Box 13)
    - Showerings, 1961-1966 (Box 13)
    - Singer, 1954-1978; 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Smith & Nephew, 1961-1976 (Box 13)
    - Solavent, 1983 (Box 13)
    - Sotheby, 1959-1971 (Box 13)
    - South African Citrus, 1959-1962 (Box 13)
    - Spillers, 1958-1969 (Box 13)
    - Taylor Woodrow, 1962-1978 (Box 13)
    - Taylor Woods, 1962 (Box 13)
    - Tea cooperative campaign, 1963-1973 (Box 14)
    - Tesco, 1962-1974; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - The Times, 1946-1964 (Box 14)
    - Times Furnishing, 1963 (Box 14)
    - Tobias Braude (Thomas Braude), 1975-1977 (Box 14)
    - Tootals, 1965-1967 (Box 14)
    - Trafford Warehouse, 1963 (Box 14)
    - Triplex, 1964 (Box 14)
    - Tube Investments, 1964-1965 (Box 14)
    - Typhoo Tea, 1961-1967 (Box 14)
    - Unigate (United Dairies), 1965-1979 (Box 14)
    - Union Carbide, 1963-1974 (Box 14)
    - United Biscuits, 1961-1978; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - United Drapery Stores, 1961-1963 (Box 14)
    - United Fruit, 1959 (Box 14)
    - Van Melle/Fruitella, 1983 (Box 21)
    - Vick, 1964-1971 (Box 14)
    - Vickers Armstrong, 1961-1967 (Box 14)
    - Viyella, 1963-1968 (Box 14)
    - Wall's Meat, 1961-1981 (Box 14)
    - Wilkinson Sword, 1961-1979 (Box 14)
    - Wrigley, 1966-1971 (Box 14)
    - Yardley, 1969-1972 (Box 15)
  - Accounts Gained, 1960-1970; 2
    - A-N, 1966-1968 (Box 15)
    - Gardisett: Net Curtains, 1966-1968 (Box 15)
    - Gramco, 1968-1969 (Box 15)
    - Harris Lebus, 1963-1966 (Box 15)
    - House of Seagram: 100 Pipers, 1967-1969 (Box 15)
    - M-Z, 1964-1970 (Box 15)
    - Union Castle/Canaries Hotels, 1960-1966 (Box 15)
    - Warner-Lambert, 1967-1970 (Box 15)
  - Background Research, 1951-1978 and undated; 3
    - Blankets and duvets, undated (Box 15)
    - Building societies, 1967-1978 (Box 15)
    - Sewing machines, 1956-1961 (Box 16)
    - Shoes, 1951-1972; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Stationery, magazines, 1956-1969 (Box 16)
    - Stock exchange, 1953-1971 (Box 16)
    - Telephone advertising, 1966 (Box 16)
    - Tobacco, 1953-1969 (Box 16)
    - Tyres, 1952-1974; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Tyres, 1952-1974 (Box 17)
    - Travel, 1963-1972 (Box 17)
    - Wallpaper manufacturers, 1963-1970 (Box 17)